Come to me.
A guardian angel.
A spirit of comfort.
Spirit of any celestial sphere.
Anything.
Hear my call.
Come to me.
You.
You wakened me from an
eternity of darkness.
You... You...
You are not for the living.
You are not for human kind.
And shall you be one
with me ever-eternally?
Do you swear it?
I swear.
Thomas.
Thomas?
What's that. my love?
What is it?
Nothing. I...
I dreamt... I...
Come here.
There's nothing to
be afraid of. hmm?
The honeymoon was yet too short.
Take off your shoes.
I wish I could stay. my love.
How should I have earned
such a doting wife?
Ellen.
I told you not to
let her into bed.
Everything I wear.
absolutely covered in it.
But Greta loves it here.
She wishes you to stay. too.
Today is of the utmost
importance for us.
One minute more.
I really must be off.
Goodbye.
He has the position already.
They'll send him away.
Morning.
Excuse me.
You have kept him
a quarter hour.
Forgive me. sir.
Pray. pardon me. Herr Knock.
for my tardiness.
Your delay is providential.
my boy. providential.
Come in. come in.
Still preparing the account.
Uh. and I thank you.
sir. for considering me.
When tidings of your recent
nuptials reached my ears.
I knew it was providence.
A new husband
requires new wages.
You're too generous. sir.
Allow me to extend my
congratulations to your wife.
Thank you. sir.
She truly is beautiful.
A... a nonpareil.
Almost a...
sylph.
Yes. Thank you. sir.
Uh. and I'm most
eager to proceed
with whatever your request.
that I might be fully
engaged with the firm.
Indeed. indeed.
Providence.
Now. I have been entertaining
dealings with a foreign count.
Very old line of nobility.
Very old and... eccentric.
He wishes to acquire a
home here in our Wisburg.
- Oh. yes?
- To retire here.
He has one foot in the
grave. so to speak.
Uh. I should be pleased
to escort the gentleman
and recommend him
to our properties.
I have already selected
Gruünewald Manor.
Forgive me. sir. but is
it not. well. uh. a ruin?
He requested an old home.
and he will pay most generously.
I shall meet him tomorrow.
then... nine of the clock?
Here
is the peculiarity.
He's too infirm to travel.
so you needs must
journey to him.
I see.
He lives in a small
country east of Bohemia.
isolated in the Carpathian Alps.
Oh.
It will be a great
adventure. my boy.
Indeed.
Uh. may not the count execute
the deed here when he arrives?
Oh. no. it is much too urgent.
He insists we offer
him an agent...
in the flesh.
And he will reward you
handsomely. my boy. handsomely.
Secure this account. and
you will secure your...
official position in the firm.
Thank you. sir. Thank you.
I shan't disappoint.
And what was the count's name?
Orlok.
And I shall have
to set off tomorrow.
as it is a six-week journey.
But Harding has
generously agreed
to keep you till my return.
Why have you killed
these beautiful flowers?
- What?
- Nothing.
- What are you talking about?
- Forgive me.
Uh. let us put them in water.
They will only
die in a few days.
- Throw them out.
- What?
Throw them out!
What are you...
You cannot leave.
What is this?
I must tell you my dream.
Ellen. we have put these
difficulties behind us.
- I must.
- Please.
No more of your
childhood memories.
- The doctors advised never...
- No.
It was our wedding.
Yet not in chapel walls.
Above was an
impenetrable thundercloud
outstretched beyond the hills.
The scent of the lilacs was
strong in the rain. and...
when I reached the altar...
you weren't there.
Standing before
me. all in black.
was...
Death.
But I was so happy.
So very happy.
We exchanged vows. we embraced.
and when we turned around.
everyone was dead.
Father
and... everyone.
The stench of their
bodies was horrible.
And...
But I'd never been so happy
as that moment...
as I held hands with Death.
Never speak these things aloud.
Never.
It is a trifle. a foolish dream.
just as your past fancies.
Everything is well.
It portends something
awful for us.
Look. when I return.
I will finally make
something of myself.
I shall buy us a fine house of
our own with a maidservant...
We needn't any of that.
I wish you to have
all you deserve.
You mustn't leave.
I love you too much.
Pray. stop.
Never since
our school days. Tom.
- From my grandfather. the best.
- Uh. uh. no. I oughtn't.
Uh. it's worth celebrating
your adventure.
Thank you.
Mm.
- I envy you.
- Mm.
I-I envy you.
You've truly taken your
father's place now.
It's incredible.
The bloody responsibility. it's
crushing. Thomas. crushing.
Of course. it's
unseemly to complain
with all the earnings. but
the demands of the market
grow faster than
the damned shipyard.
And my two girls... two. Tom.
I... I love them
more than the world.
And... speak
none of this to Ellen
or my Anna. but we have
another on the way.
- Mm-hmm.
- Congratulations.
Hey. you always
were a rutting goat.
- I cannot resist her.
- Mm.
And when will you two newlyweds?
When I'm no longer a pauper.
Uh. Friedrich. when I
have. I mean to say.
I shall finally
be able to return
- the moneys you loaned me.
- Not another word.
- Uh. and. Friedrich?
- Hmm?
Do take care of Ellen.
She nearly begged
me to remain here.
And toss aside your
fine opportunity?
I fear her past.
uh. melancholy returning.
Naturally. Her
dashing young husband's
leaving her bedside
cold.
My sweet ones.
it's time now for bed.
Papa! Papa!
No!
Listen.
then. to your mother.
The time has
simply come. Enough now.
- Come on. All right.
- Come.
We can't! There is a
monster in the room!
Papa! Papa!
Don't let her feed
me to the monster.
Stab him!
Pardon us. but I am
to hunt a monster.
You're a perfect child yourself.
- Good night.
Up we go. Come.
Papa. please
stay with us!
I will stay with
you until you are fast asleep.
I can hear him
breathing beneath my bed!
Nonsense. my darling.
You are safe and sound.
Forgive me.
I have put these
fancies behind me.
I have.
And we have each other.
Your lordship. it is entirely
as you have demanded.
He shall presently
be in thy rule.
and I shall attend thee here.
near the object of thy contract!
- I'm proud of you.
- Mm.
Please keep safe.
Have you so little faith in me?
I will send you my utmost faith.
And you will write
to me every day.
I shall. I promise.
Remember. it's all for us.
- I love you.
Farewell.
Thank you.
Okay.
I'm sorry. Sorry. no.
What
is all this barking?
Get out. you filthy gypsies!
You bring shame to my inn.
And you bring me trouble.
Uh. forgive me. I-I only
wish to stay one night.
I have an audience
at the castle.
Castle Orlok. beyond
the AÁrnyék Pass...
By God's name. never
speak of that castle.
Return to your
country. foreigner.
Shut your mouths!
May the holy mind
of God bugger you!
I am weary. I-I pray you.
Go.
I will pay double the board.
I banish you. I banish
you with garlic.
Please. please don't go there.
Beware of his shadow.
The shadow covers
you in a nightmare.
Awake. but a dream.
There is no escape.
Pray.
Pray. Pray.
Bless this virgin child.
Bless her.
Guide our stallion to
the unclean spirit.
The vampire!
The vampire's grave!
Find his tail!
His cloven hooves!
Silence!
God send you burst!
No. by the grace of God!
Hello?
My horse?
You are late.
The midnight hour has passed.
And my attendants
have all retired.
Forgive me. Count.
Leave there
your conveniences.
Set out the deed and sit.
Would you not wish
to wait till morning?
I wish you to do as I request.
Yes.
Of course. sir.
Lord.
Pardon me. sir?
Your lord.
I will be addressed
as the honor of my
blood demands it.
Yes. my lord.
Forgive me. my lord.
Pray...
sit.
Thank you. my lord.
I am most impatient
to bring my eyes on
your covenant papers.
And my correspondence
with your proprietor.
Herr Knock.
I have long awaited them.
Of course. my lord.
Drink.
I have. my lord...
uh. I have questions
about the. um. unfamiliar
customs of the peasantry
and the errant wanderers.
Last night. I saw...
or. rather. I believe I
saw a band of gypsies.
They ventured to a
small birch grove and...
I fear we yet keep close
many superstitions here
that may seem backward
to a young man of
your high learning.
These gypsies. they
exhumed a corpse.
It is their filthy ritual.
What manner of ritual...
Speak not of it again!
How I look forward to retiring
to your city of a modern mind...
who knows nothing of
nor believes any such
morbid fairy tales.
Eat.
You are married. Herr Hutter?
Take heed what you do.
It's nothing.
I might ease your wound.
Come by the fire.
Your face shows you unwell.
Wait for me!
Careful. children.
Keep from that filth.
Catch me!
Do you ever feel at times
as if you were not...
as if you were not a person?
- Well. I...
- What I wish to say is that
you are not truly
present nor alive.
as if you were at the whim
of another. like a doll.
and someone or
something had the power
to breathe life into you.
to move you.
Well. of course we all
feel out of sorts at times.
It's not out of sorts.
It's... it's as if there is
something at play that is too
awful or grave to explain.
- God.
- No. my lovely Anna.
I...
Look at the sky.
Look at the sea.
Does it never call
to you. urge you?
Something is close at hand.
That is his power.
A gentle breeze from heaven.
Destiny!
My sweet romantic.
I am not mad. Anna.
Leni.
Forgive me.
Everything I say
sounds so childish.
Your words spring from
your honest heart.
My heart is lost
without my Thomas.
Hello?
Count?
And your signature
as solicitor.
How careless of me. my lord.
The language of my forefathers.
Of course.
A maiden's token. I see.
Your bride?
Just so. It. uh...
Yes.
May I?
We are newly
married of late.
Incidentally. I
have letters to her
I would post. if I may.
Lilac.
What was that. my lord?
You are fortunate in your love.
It's providence. as
Herr Knock would say.
Your signature.
I pray...
you will indulge my pardon.
I durst not neglect
your commission.
Herr Hutter.
Now are we neighbors.
It is my good fortune. my lord.
Forgive my asking. my lord.
but why such an antique
residence as Gruünewald Manor?
The covenant is signed.
Of course.
Well. I thank you
and congratulate you
on your new home.
It is late.
You must wish to retire.
If I may. my lord.
i-if I may be slightly
unsubtle in my approach.
I-I wish to depart as soon as...
well. as soon as agreeable
my services rendered.
I am much...
I have been enduring the
most irregular dreams.
I fear I am taken ill.
It is a black omen to
journey in poor health.
You will remain and
well rest yourself.
Uh. I must
object. my lord.
You will obey
this. my counsel.
Uh. but. my lord...
Count?
Y-You have my locket.
Your husband is lost to you.
Dream of me.
Only me.
In mild cases of
somnambulism... sleepwalking...
it is brought on by a
congestion of the blood.
Too much blood.
Perhaps... perhaps
she was oppressed
in a somewhat odd
position beforehand.
Yet she has had these
fits in the past.
- Troubled nerves and so on.
- I see.
Well. if it continues. let
me know. but until then.
uh. keep it from your
worries. my dear fellow.
Yes. of course.
I am disposed to recommend
that she sleep in her corset.
It encourages correct posture.
calms the womb and
revives circulation.
Yes. very well.
And. uh. if her
stirring escalates.
you can always tie
her to the bed.
Oh. he's coming to me.
He's coming.
I'll increase the ether.
Nothing of Thomas? Nothing?
No. I mean. yes. I've
received nothing of any kind.
Not even to your...
at the shipyard?
And Herr Knock?
Still no trace of him.
His firm is in daily chaos.
I never liked that man. Never.
I shall call upon his
office myself directly.
- Please. Frau Hutter. no.
- I must discover something.
- Oh. for heaven's sake!
- But Thomas...
You cannot leave unaccompanied.
I am most sensitive
to your ardent nature
and shan't reprove you further
in this error of judgment.
I will send someone daily
until Herr Knock is found.
Thomas is well.
I'm certain of it.
Leni. it's near sundown.
We really ought to be leaving.
Leni?
Just a moment longer.
Please.
Friedrich. be not
a churl. please.
You mustn't be swept
up in her fairy ways.
The entirety of the household
centers upon her whims.
I tire of discussing her.
Think you there is no
burden upon myself?
I love her.
She is blameless for her malady.
Forgive me. my love.
Dr. Sievers will pay
her another visit.
Let us only please
talk of something else.
How is our little Friedrich. hmm?
Well. hungry as always.
- Like his father.
- Mm.
Friedrich. in public?
I cannot resist you. my love.
Ellen?
Leni!
New patient?
Yes. sir.
Uh. we stowed him
downstairs. sir.
I have strictly forbidden
the use of the old cells.
- Begging your pardon. sir.
- It's out of the question.
This is a modern
hospital. not a prison.
A little old soul he may
look. but on my life.
saw him screaming
and a-groaning.
Found him at the Luther
Christmas Market.
Killed three sheep
with his bare hands.
And he was eating them raw-like.
Raw!
Good day. mein Herr.
I am Dr. Sievers.
What seems to be the trouble?
No trouble.
Providence. Providence.
I see.
Can you tell me
your name. Herr...?
I am no one.
I am his servant.
And. um. what do you have there?
Lives. gifts.
bestowed upon me
by his lordship.
Look. this is a pretty one.
His lordship likes the
pretty ones...
best.
His lordship?
He is infinity.
Eyes shining
like a jeweled diadem.
And then putrescence.
Asphyxience.
And devourence.
Now. my good fellow.
why would you do that?
It's all right.
No one wants to hurt
you. my dear friend.
He is coming.
Who?
Who is?
'Twas he that invoked me.
'Twas I that was
chosen to serve him.
for I know what he covets.
And he shall cast upon you
curses. confusion.
afflictions. rebukes.
for you have forsaken me.
and he shall reign over
all of your empty corpses.
Devourence.
Devourence!
Harding. help me.
These hysterical spells
come over her at nightfall
like clockwork.
- Cigar?
- No. thank you.
I... lament to tell you this.
Hutter's employer. Herr Knock.
was admitted to
hospital this morning.
What?
Did you speak to him of Thomas?
- He is mad.
- Mad?
Non compos mentis.
And. Friedrich. he...
well. the wretched fellow.
while inflamed with some
sort of religious mania.
he shares a similar
motto to Frau Hutter:
"He is coming."
What?
Where the devil are you. Thomas?
Which brings
me to the specialist.
A man by the name of von Franz.
- Swiss.
- Swiss?
Professor Albin
Eberhart von Franz.
He is the sole person who
may be able to diagnose her.
An eminent physician
and scholar in Zurich
when I was at school.
my finest teacher.
Send a message to Zurich. then.
No. no. he... he's
here in Wisburg.
Here?
Here-here?
Why haven't you told me. man?
- Well...
- This is capital news.
Damn it. man. why didn't
you think of this before?
You see. he... von Franz is
the most learned in the field.
his mind staggering.
I'll spare no expense.
No. you misunderstand
me. Friedrich.
It has fallen hard on
me to recommend him.
He was tossed out
of the university.
laughed out of his home country.
- What?
- Grieves me to say it. but...
he became obsessed with
the work of Paracelsus.
Agrippa and the like.
I am a shipman. Sievers.
Alchemy.
Mystic philosophy.
The occult.
No! Orlok!
A black enchanter
he was in life.
Solomonar.
The devil preserved his soul
that his corpse may
walk again in blasphemy.
You are lost in his shadow.
No. No. I must leave.
I promised Ellen.
Remain here.
His evil cannot enter
this house of God.
I promised I'd join the firm.
I came here to sell the
count a house in Wisburg.
He cannot leave here.
- He is bound for Wisburg.
- He cannot leave here.
He must return to
the cursed earth
wherein he was buried.
No! He seeks after Ellen.
I know it!
Soon I will no longer
be a shadow to you.
Soon our flesh shall embrace
and we shall be as one.
Nature. increase thy thunders
and hasten me upon the wings
of thy barbarous winds.
Thy promised gift awaits!
Providence!
The scientific
community is on a crusade
to prove his work
drove him to madness.
- Hmm.
- I assure you.
Harding. the professor may
be a bit unconventional.
but he will know the
source of her malady.
Professor von Franz?
Leave me be.
It is your former student.
Avaunt!
Begone. I say!
Professor. please.
I should not wish to intrude.
I had nearly
unlocked the final key
of the Mysteriorum
Libri Quinque.
I'm sorry. Professor.
No. No matter.
I miscalculated the stars.
Hermes will not render my
black sulfur gold this evening.
Yes. we shan't
trouble you further.
- We must take our leave.
- Just...
Good night. Professor.
Nolite dare sanctum canibus.
Neque mittatis margaritas
vestra ante porcos.
My dear young Sievers.
Or do my dying eyes deceive me?
I should've known.
Embrace me. my boy.
I am so rejoiced to see you.
I sensed something.
It brought me to Wisburg
all these years ago.
I felt it was now
imminently approaching.
I thought it ill. but
it must have been you.
Now. what is the matter?
Ah. I see. yes.
A dear friend of yours
has some rare ailment.
Perhaps a houseguest. yes?
A young woman exhibiting
protracted fits of somnambulism.
You look tired. young man.
Schnapps?
Wait! You are not yet well!
Yeah?
Quick. Captain.
Back to the
quarterdeck with you.
But Vasilyev. And now Redenko.
Captain. it's the plague.
Quarantine the sick!
The Devil!
Our cargo is cursed.
Back away! Back away!
Out! Everyone out!
Untie this child at once!
It's all I could do to keep her
from tearing the
room to ribbons.
Untie her.
You are the doctor
our Sievers spoke of?
Drugged?
I have been
administering an opiate.
She must rest by day. for
her body is in utter stress
- all the night.
- She cannot be clouded.
Step away. Step away.
My dear creature.
yes. I am he. and I am
hither come to help you.
Is she yours?
Greta?
She has no master nor mistress.
Quite so.
I entreat you to excuse me.
but I should like to begin
my consultation presently.
You see. I have a
curiosity about you.
Dr. Sievers tells me that
you have had these spells
since childhood.
Would you describe
them to me. please?
I cannot always remember them.
As if my spirit wanders off.
Tell me what you can.
from the beginning.
Sometimes it was...
it is like a dream.
- Hmm.
- And I know things.
I always knew the contents
of my Christmas gifts.
I knew when that my
mother would pass.
Father. he would find me in
our fields within the forest
as if I was his little
changeling girl.
I see.
But as I became
older. it worsened.
I frightened him.
My touch.
I was so very alone. you see.
and I wished for comfort.
Then a presence
and the nightmares.
the epilepsies. I...
Pray. continue.
At last. Papa found
me once laying.
Unclothed. I was.
My body. my...
my flesh. I...
"Sin."
"Sin." he said.
He would have sent me to
that place. I... I shan't go.
No. no.
It all ended when I
first met my Thomas.
From our love. I
became as normal.
Yet these visions
and night wanderings
have returned to you?
I fear for him so.
Professor.
My dreams grow darker.
Does evil come from
within us or from beyond?
Her trance
state is begun.
You have bled her to
decrease the congestion?
Of course.
And her
menstruations are also?
Liberal.
Too much
blood. Too much blood.
A taper. please.
Her pupil is expanded.
It does not contract
naturally to light.
- Impossible.
- A second sight.
She is no longer here.
My bag.
Forgive the
grotesque tediousness
of this demonstration.
The needle.
However. I must impress upon you
that this child is not with us.
Professor. I do protest.
Restrain your protestation.
for she feels nothing.
She communes now
with another realm.
Tend to the wound. Sievers.
Now...
Do you hear me. my child?
And what then do you see?
I charge you. speak
now what you see.
Enduring night.
A specter of death.
He... he spreads his shadow.
and he... he... he is coming.
Who? Who is coming
to you. my child?
Who. damn you? Speak!
Yield before this
ancient talisman!
Professor!
I will not harm her!
I command you.
hearken to my voice.
By the protection of
Chamuel. Haniel and Zadkiel.
impart your speech unto me.
In the name of Eligos.
Orabas and Asmoday.
impart your speech unto me.
I shall
persist to join you
every night... first in
sleep. then in your arms.
Everything will be mixed
with abomination. and you'll
be knee-deep in blood.
Everyone will cry.
There will be none
to bury the dead.
- You are promised to me!
- Promised?
- She means her husband!
Help me! Help me!
As I feared.
Well?
"Well" what. my
boy? Cannot you see?
See what?
See that she is cursed.
- Cursed?
- Yes. cursed.
This dear young creature is
possessed of some spirit.
Perhaps a demon.
I beg your pardon.
I assure
you. Harding.
the professor means
this as hyperbole.
- No. I mean a demon.
- You jest.
But what of your own discoveries
of macabre hallucination
pathologies?
This is not one.
You cannot conceivably
have perceived all of this.
How should this happen to Ellen?
Demonic spirits more
easily obsess those
whose lower animal
functions dominate.
Demons like them.
They seek them out.
I do not wish to
dispute you. Professor.
but I myself have witnessed
women of nervous constitutions
invent all manner of delusion.
This is no delusion.
I believe she has always
been highly conductive
to these cosmic
forces. uniquely so.
Your lunatic. perhaps.
Do you then acknowledge a
connection between these cases?
That is the question.
Oh. this is just capital.
I tell you. it is the manner
of her husband's disappearance.
No. This evil...
what it is. how it
has been summoned.
unleashed. I know not.
but this remarkable child
it has chained itself to
is in grave peril.
I must to my studies.
Frau Harding.
Sit with her. Observe her.
Report her behavior.
Sievers. no more ether.
But she will rave all the night.
Then rave she must.
There is a dread storm rising.
I will end this
plague. This devil.
- Help me. Help me!
- Oh. dear. Oh. my.
I'll get you out.
Don't you worry.
Help.
It's all right. It's all right.
- Listen.
- What was that?
Listen.
His lordship... he has come!
The blood is the life.
He's here. He's here!
His lordship is here!
The blood is the life!
He's here!
Ellen?
Thomas!
No. no!
Thomas.
He hasn't found you.
I-I feared I'd
never see you again.
My love.
You were right.
You were.
He... he has your locket.
Thomas.
What
the hell is it now?
- Thomas!
- Hartmann. the door!
Very good. sir.
Thomas!
Mama! Papa!
Is that the monster?
What the devil is this?
It's past 3:00 in the morning.
My God.
Plague. It's a plague ship.
Damn it.
Alert the port authority.
- And fetch Dr. Sievers.
- Aye. aye. sir.
There it is. your lordship.
There it is.
The broker lives.
I shall stifle out the
bridegroom. your lordship.
I have use in him.
Pray...
Instruct me.
Charge me. Use me.
I shall fetch unto thee
thy pretty belonging?
The compact commands
she must willingly
repledge her vow.
She cannot be stolen.
Yet. my lord...
I beg thee...
Silence. dog!
Your entreaties grow insolent.
You shall crave of me nothing.
My lord.
Daybreak draws near.
Anon. the bells of dawn
shall toll in
despair of my coming.
And I shall taste of you.
How is he faring?
I fear no better than everyone
tells me I have suffered.
Pray. forgive me for all the
troubles I have caused you.
I am only glad you have
become yourself again.
It seems a miracle.
Perhaps Professor
Franz was wrong.
Perhaps it was only your
wish to see Thomas returned
and your... your...
My melancholy?
- Uh. I...
- Thomas has seen
something awful.
If only I could speak
to the profess...
Hush. His thoughts
are so queer.
Professor Franz said a demon.
Leni. please.
For the sake of the children.
Christmastide is upon us.
Why must you remain so
exasperatingly contrary?
Because I am in the right.
Sievers. I requested conference
with your maniac.
not a dead man.
I beg your patience. Professor.
but this is what vexes me.
He exhibits all the
signs of a blood plague.
Sepsis. ophthalmic discharge.
Even flagrant rodent
bites here and here.
I fear this ship has brought
the plague to Wisburg.
And what is confounding is
his body is entirely
absent of blood.
Look at this curious mark here.
Huh.
I've seen some leviathan-like
pests in our canals.
but tell me. Professor. what
rat has jaws of such size?
Angels and demons protect us.
Where is your lunatic?
You must take me
to him presently.
Ain't you heard. Doctor. sir?
No.
Herr Knock has gone and escaped.
What?
He killed the porter
on duty last night.
This man must be found.
Sirrah. show me out.
Sievers. fetch Harding.
And meet me at my
residence tonight.
This is no mere plague.
Get off me.
Give me room.
Thomas.
- I-I can't breathe.
- It's me.
I-I can't breathe.
Get off!
Please you. don't
leave us. Mama.
I promise I shan't
let anything harm you.
No monsters. Nothing.
Now. give me a kiss.
And say your prayers.
Now I lay
me down to sleep.
I pray the Lord my soul to keep.
Anna?
Oh. Oh. you frightened me.
Forgive me.
Has Friedrich returned?
Uh. uh. no. No.
What is it. my lovely?
May I...
stay with you tonight?
Our friendship is a
precious balm to my heart.
Forgive my chiding you.
Thank you for loving me.
You may take it if you wish.
God is with us. Leni.
I cannot yield to being
haunted by a ghost.
Oh. no. please. No.
It is no mere ghost. for
it can manifest physically
and with the most foul intent.
And what. pray. is that?
Like every plague.
its soul desire
is to consume all life on Earth.
This creature is a force
more powerful than evil.
It is Death itself.
I have not slept in days.
My house has become a bedlam.
and here I've been resummoned
to this godforsaken
habitation for this?
Do not tell me you believe
in such medieval devilry!
I do not believe. I know!
I have seen things in this world
that would've made
Isaac Newton crawl
back into his mother's womb.
We have not become
so much enlightened
as we have been blinded by
the gaseous light of science.
I have wrestled with the devil
as Jacob wrestled
the angel in Peniel.
And I tell you. if we
are to tame darkness.
we must first face
that it exists.
Meine Herren.
we are here encountering
the undead plague carrier.
the Vampyr Nosferatu.
You.
I have felt you
crawling like a
serpent in my body.
It is not me.
It is your nature.
No. I love Thomas.
Love is inferior to you.
I told you. you are
not of humankind.
You are a villain to speak so.
I am an appetite.
Nothing more.
O'er centuries.
a loathsome beast
I lay within the darkest pit.
Till you did wake
me. enchantress.
and stirred me from my grave.
You are my affliction.
I care nothing of
your afflictions.
Yet even now we are fated.
Your husband has signed his name
and covenanted you to my person
for but a sack of gold.
- Lies.
- For gold.
he did absolve his nuptial bond.
You know nothing of him.
And the resignation
must be completed by you
freely of thine own will.
You are a deceiver.
You deceive yourself.
I was but an innocent child.
And thought you I
would not return?
Thought you I would not?
Your passion is bound to me.
You cannot love.
I cannot.
Yet I cannot be
sated without you.
Remember how once we were?
A moment. Remember?
I abhor you.
You are false!
So you wish me to prove
my enmity as well?
I will leave you three nights.
Tonight was the first.
Tonight you denied yourself.
and thereby. you suffer me
to vanish up the lives
of those you love.
Denied myself?
You revel in my torture.
Upon the third night.
you will submit.
or he you call your husband
shall perish by my hand.
No.
Till you bid me come
shall you watch the
world become as naught.
No!
Two more nights.
I ain't
never seen the like.
It's been a-spreading faster
than wildfire since yestermorn.
We simply cannot admit any more.
The contraction
rate is too high.
I've entreated the
burgomaster for a quarantine.
- The city must be shut up.
- It ain't Christian.
We can find rooms. sir.
The day of judgment's
a-coming. sir. Take pity.
We must remain calm
in the face of this plague.
A shadow pressing.
My body sinking.
Sinking.
The smell of rancid meat.
Suffocating.
I...
I feel so weak. I...
I fear little
Friedrich is so strong.
so hungry he is eating me weary.
May I... may I see the girls?
I must assure them...
Everything will be
well. my darling.
Everything shall be just fine.
I don't know myself.
Ellen. tell me.
what is this
insufferable darkness?
I...
Herr Harding. you must see me.
There is something.
The shadow. an
infernal creature.
- Ellen.
- Please!
These are no troubled nerves.
It is as Professor Franz
described... a demon.
Frau Hutter. forgive me.
but I need you and Thomas...
both of you... to return home.
What?
It's for your own sake.
Please.
Have pity. Thomas
is very poorly.
I know not what I...
I shall pray for Tom.
- You know I love you both.
- What of Anna?
Did you not see her?
It's none of your concern.
Friedrich. you
must listen to me.
We're all in the
most grave danger.
I throw myself at your feet!
Frau Hutter. please!
Why do you hate me?
How dare you speak to me
in that marked manner?
You have never liked me. Never.
Know your place. madam.
I will not stand by and
pretend at your superiority.
I refuse to exchange
- reproaches with you.
- Why can you not hear me?
Listen to me. please!
I have done
everything in my power
to be kind to you in
these long months.
Tied me up.
Find the dignity to display
the respect to your caretaker.
How can you be so
stupid and cruel?
Hartmann will call you a coach.
My expense. of course.
And for your husband's
sake. I pray you learn
to conduct yourself
with more deference.
Anna is going to die.
You are going to die!
We're all going to die!
Why did you not tell
me of this before?
I am a fool.
Of course it is Herr Knock.
His obsessive consumption
of living creatures...
it must be him.
He is not Nosferatu.
But he must be found.
for he has made compact
with this shadow.
Search everything.
Pull up the rug.
Solomonari.
And their codex of secrets.
"Then I stood on
the sand by the sea.
"And I saw a beast
rising out of the sea.
"And the serpent gave
the beast authority...
"to speak of great
names in blasphemy.
"And the beast had
the form of a leopard.
"the feet of a bear.
the mouth of a lion!
"A beast with seven
heads and ten horns!
"On each horn a crown.
on each head a
blasphemous name..."
Our somnambulist and her husband
are in incomparable danger.
I must see them.
I sent them home.
How can this
perversion be killed?
I do not know. You
sent them home?
- What?
- You sent them home?
No. not that. Yes. I did.
You don't know?
Precisely. Correct.
I do not know.
I have never encountered
Nosferatu firsthand.
He doesn't know.
All your fine lectures
are mere regurgitations
from bloody books!
The means of repelling
and destroying
vary greatly from
region to region.
Their efficacy is
plainly unknown.
Yet there is one invariable fact
- that interests me most.
- Go on.
In every account. the
Nosferatu must return
to the earth wherein
it was buried
by first crow of cock.
It must sleep in
its grave by day.
What happens if it does not?
That. my dear Sievers.
is the question.
Oh. God.
My God.
I am shattering.
I'm breaking apart. Get out.
- Har-Harding.
- Take your leave at once.
Both of you!
Friedrich. please.
we do not wish to...
Can't you see there's a
bloody real plague. gentlemen?
A real epidemic that is
really killing real people.
- Damn you. Harding!
- Oh. the pair of you!
I'm sorry. Sievers. I'm sorry.
Frau Hutter is mad
and should have been
locked up long ago.
My Anna...
was bitten by vermin.
Rats! No more.
Tomorrow. we are
leaving Wisburg.
But the quarantine... tomorrow.
we close off the city.
I'm not gonna let your
vain madness kill my wife.
The night demon has supped
of your good wife's blood
and shall return for the rest.
Leave.
Oh. Thomas.
Ellen. my love.
We must go.
We must flee the city.
You're in danger.
- You knew...
- We cannot run.
No. we must.
There is something
I must tell you.
Something so loathsome. so base.
Nothing you can
say will shake me.
for there is a
devil in this world.
and I have met him. and he...
I cannot speak it. He...
He is come to Wisburg for you.
I know.
What?
I know him.
Know him?
I've brought this evil upon us.
I have never shared my...
secret with any soul.
I sought company.
I sought...
tenderness. and I called out.
- What do you mean by this?
- At first. it was sweet.
- I had never known such bliss.
- Ellen.
Yet it
turned to torture.
It would kill me.
But. Thomas...
it was you that gave me the
courage to be free of my shame.
You.
What are you telling me?
Don't you understand?
Pray. help me to.
He is my shame. He
is my melancholy.
He took me as his lover then.
and now he has come back.
He has discovered our
marriage and has come back.
Impossible.
He stalks me in my dreams.
All my sleeping thoughts
are of him every night.
- Ellen.
- Don't touch me!
I am not to be touched.
You stopped your letters to me.
What?
You promised to write
to me every day.
Did not you think of
me in that castle?
I did. I...
Lies.
After what you have
just confessed. how...
He told me about you.
He told me how foolish you were.
How fearful.
How like a child.
How you fell into his arms as
a swooning lily of a woman.
Ellen.
He told me how you sold
me to him for gold.
- No. I...
-Our love was supposed to be sacred!
- Ellen. please.
- You never listen!
Well. where is it?
Your money? Your
promotion? Your house?
Where is that which
is so precious to you?
Have you paid back
kind Harding your debt?
Have you repaid him with this
plague that infects his wife?
I left for us. for our future.
For what? For what?
For these things!
- For you!
- It doesn't matter!
It doesn't matt...
Can't you see?
We should never have married.
We're already dead!
Ellen. please.
Ellen!
I-I shall send for Dr. Sievers.
No! Please. please.
I'll be good. I
promise. I promise.
You could never
please me as he could.
Yes! Take me!
Please.
Please!
Yes!
Kiss me.
Kiss my heart. My heart.
Let him see. Let
him see our love.
Without you. I will
become a demon.
Ellen. Ellen! Ellen!
Ellen. it's me. Ellen.
Ellen. I love you. I love you.
You're safe with me.
It's me. It's me.
Keep away from
me. I am unclean.
Never.
He will murder you if
I do not go to him.
We will be torn apart. and
the world will be despair.
No.
I'll kill him.
Kill him I will.
He shall never harm you again.
Never.
At last.
"And lo. the maiden fair
"did offer up her
love unto the beast
"and with him lay
in close embrace
"until the first cock crow.
"Her willing sacrifice
thus broke the curse
and freed them from the
plague of Nosferatu."
She is the way.
Wake not.
Papa! Papa!
Friedrich. Friedrich!
Friedrich. wake up.
I can weep no longer. for I
have no more tears to shed.
We must speak with him.
Just a moment longer.
His grief is too great.
May I?
More will be taken.
- She was with child.
- I know.
The grim reaper wields
his heavy scythe
with every change of wind.
Professor. I must
speak with you.
And I would speak with you.
Take that blackguard
from this place!
- Your diseased mind...
- Please. Please.
Has brought all of this outrage!
- Stop this.
- Stop. please. It is my fault.
This moment doesn't
concern you. Thomas.
- Your very presence...
-Your horror has rent our hearts.
- but you must hear us.
- Does me wrong!
Friedrich. these
nightmares do exist!
They exist.
And yet he shows no sign
of the blood plague.
The good sisters
sought to nurse me
back to health
with their prayer.
yet I fear I'm not
free of his spell.
Trust in God and your strength.
The monster left you to the
wolves. yet you prevailed.
Harding.
Forgive me. I'm
not myself. I...
Please forgive me. all of you.
My reason could not
accept... accept...
Strength. man. Strength.
Orlok has kept his coffin
within Gruünewald Manor?
- Assuredly.
- Under our very noses.
Tonight. we destroy the beast.
- Let me come with you.
- No. of course not. Ellen.
You must be kept safe away.
We shall meet at Harding's
and depart for the manor.
Please. The readiness is all.
We shall sanctify the
earth wherein he is buried
and destroy the sarcophagus.
Then he can have no
sanctuary at cock crow.
And when we uncover the body?
I will drive a spike of
cold iron through him.
- What if it does not work?
- It must.
Professor. allow me to
walk you to your door.
I know... it must
be me. Professor.
I am but an able tourist
in this occult world.
You were born to it.
It is a rare gift.
His pull to me is so powerful.
so terrible.
yet my spirit cannot
be evil as his.
We must know evil to
be able to destroy it.
We must discover it
within ourselves.
And when we have. we must
crucify the evil within us.
or there is no salvation.
I need no salvation.
My entire life. I have done
no ill but heed my nature.
Then hearken to it.
I fear Nosferatu is impervious
to any of our iron stakes.
I'm convinced only you
have the faculty to redeem us.
Ellen.
let us make haste.
In heathen times.
you might have been a
great priestess of Isis.
Yet. in this strange
and modern world.
your purpose is
of greater worth.
You are our salvation.
Thank you.
I will keep your
husband at bay tonight.
Go now. Go home.
Attend him that he is
sturdy for this false hunt.
You will put an
end to all of this?
Promise you shan't return
to me till he is no more.
- Promise me you won't return.
- I promise.
He does not have power
over you. Thomas.
I place my utter faith in you.
I love you.
Fear not.
Goodbye.
He is not here?
No. Mr. Harding
has departed. sir.
Where could he have gone?
He has a heavy grief.
We shall wait for him.
There's time yet till sundown.
No. we must find him.
He is unwell. Sievers.
I fear for him.
- Harding!
Friedrich!
Clara.
Louise.
Oh. my girls.
Anna.
Your bed is so dark.
So small.
Anna. my love.
Our son.
Our little son.
Forgive me.
I shall never sleep again.
Never.
Let this. your tender embrace.
keep me now in bliss.
away from everlasting sleep.
Friedrich!
Oh. God.
We are too late.
We must set fire to
their infected bodies.
Our flames will sanctify them.
I cannot bear any more.
Please. we must onward.
But Orlok... will he
not already have risen?
Should we not
return to our homes?
No. I will not
wait till morning.
Very
wise. young Thomas.
I feel his hold
upon me this night.
May God have mercy
on their souls.
"In the
Name of Jehovah.
"and by the power and
dignity of these three Names.
"Tetragrammaton.
Anexhexeton. Primematum.
"cast thee. O thou
disobedient Spirit Nosferatu.
"into the Lake of Fire.
"there to remain
until the Day of Doom
"and not to be remembered
before the face of God
"who shall come to judge
the quick and the dead
and the world with fire."
Behold. the third night.
There is a chapel
beyond the courtyard.
Make haste. Thomas!
I am ready.
I bid you. come to me.
There he lies.
Oh. God.
Go forward. Thomas.
Set free the demon's body.
Thomas. no!
Herr Knock.
I...
relinquished him my soul.
I should have been the
Prince of Rats. immortal.
But he cares only
for his pretty bride.
- and she is his.
- Monstrous.
Strike again.
I am blasphemy.
Die. you accursed
mis-birth of hell!
Set fire to it all.
Damn it. man. he
has gone to my wife.
We must burn it.
We must destroy
all his habitation.
No sanctuary.
No. there is no time to be lost.
- He pursues Ellen.
- It must be her!
He cannot resist her blood!
You are a madman.
You knew Orlok
would not be here.
You knew it this afternoon.
Your wife wills it.
This is not moral!
God is beyond our
morals!
In vain! In vain!
You run in vain!
You cannot outrun her destiny!
Her dark bond with the
beast shall redeem us all.
for when the sun's pure light
shall break upon the dawn.
redemption!
The plague shall be lifted!
Redemption!
You accept this
of your own will?
I do.
Then the covenant is fulfilled.
Your oath re-pledged.
Yes.
So too shall be our flesh.
You are mine.
More.
Ellen.
Forgive us.
"And lo. the maiden fair
"did offer up her
love unto the beast
"and with him lay
in close embrace
"until the first cock crow.
"Her willing sacrifice
thus broke the curse
and freed them from the
plague of Nosferatu."